♪ In the not-too-distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different than you or me ♪
♪ He worked in a satellite loading bay ♪
♪ Just polishing switches to pay his way ♪
♪ He did his job well
with a cheerful face ♪
♪ But his bosses didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst ever made ♪
♪ Joel says when you got lemons ♪
♪ You make lemonade ♪
♪ Now keep in mind he can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies begin or end ♪
♪ Because he used the extra parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot Roll Call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
♪ Servo ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Crow ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself,
"It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax" ♪
♪ For "Mystery Science Theater 3000" ♪
(doors closing)
- All right, hey, thanks for coming
to "Mystery Science Theater
3000," I'm Joel Hodgson.
The guys at the station
sent me this facsimile
that the next film is called
"Invaders From the Deep."
I don't know what should
upset these people so much
that they would need to invade
or what it is they're in that's so deep.
Cambot, could you bring
that in a little bit?
Yeah, that's good.
And it's a Gene and Sylvia Anderson film.
They're the same people
that did "Fireball XL5,"
if you remember that, and it
stars the puppet, Troy Tempest,
and it looks like we've
got movie sign happening,
but always remember, it's
in super Marianation.
I'll go around, you go through.
(alarm buzzes)
(doors opening)
(dramatic music)
(mysterious music)
(tense music)
- We are constantly losing
battles to the land people.
Battles we would win if it were not
for the World Aquanaut Security Patrol.
- Oh, great Typhoon.
Show your face to Titan, leader
of the underwater city of Titanica.
(dramatic music)
All-powerful Typhoon.
Vengeance must be mine.
Only Marineville stands in our way
of a great and glorious victory.
(mysterious music)
All my subjects, your
orders, destroy Marineville.
(eerie music)
(explosion booming)
(dramatic music)
(serene music)
- [Joel] Excuse me.
- Ah, this is the life, Milly.
- Of course, Henry.
I always know what's best for you.
It's about time we got
away from noise and crowds.
- You're right, Milly.
You sure are.
Being an admiral was okay-
- Now you just relax, Henry,
we're on a beautiful island,
now just enjoy it.
- Yeah, just think, not another person
within 300 miles of us.
- Henry.
- Yeah, what is that?
- Someone's at the window.
- Well, how could it be?
We're completely alone on this island.
- But I tell you, Henry, there
was someone at the window.
- Now Milly, we spent all this dough
buying ourselves a private island
so we could be alone and lead a-
- Henry!
It's there again.
- All right, all right, Milly, calm down.
Now, let's take a look outside.
(waves crashing)
Now, what did I tell you, Milly?
No one there.
- [Joel] Sure.
- The window a strange unearthly face.
Be careful, Henry.
- All right, Milly, all right.
(tense music)
Milly, take a look at this.
- Well, what did I say, Henry?
I knew that there was someone.
- Just keep close by me, Milly.
(tense music)
- [Joel] Lettuce Man.
- Turn round very slowly.
- Oh, Henry!
- Make a foolish move and
I will destroy you both.
- Henry!
- Hush, Milly.
Do just as he says, he means business.
- I am Gadeth, the enemy of you
and all the accursed terrainians.
My mission is to destroy Troy Tempest
and capture Stingray, and you
are going to help, Admiral.
- [Man On Loudspeaker] Attention.
Stingray crew to report to
control tower immediately.
- Seems it came from Admiral Carson.
- Didn't he retire a year or two back?
- Right.
Bought an island in the Pacific.
Now here's the message.
"Lives in danger.
Request Stingray's aid immediately.
Proceed with vigor."
- "Proceed with vigor?"
Say, that's the WASP
code to warn of a trap.
- [Commander] Right again.
- I guess it means there's more to it
than just to call for help.
- You betcha.
This is a full-scale emergency.
- We're on our way, Commander.
- Okay, Troy.
Now you'll need someone
who knows the country.
Better take Marina.
(tense music)
- [Joel] She's fine.
- Okay, Marina?
Stingray crew standing by
at action stations, Control.
(tense music)
- All right, Atlanta.
Sound launch stations.
- [Atlanta] Yes sir.
(tense music)
- Here we go.
Just sit tight, Marina.
(tense music)
(dramatic music)
- Stingray launch stage one complete, sir.
- Right, Atlanta.
In view of that code message,
we ought to be prepared
for an attack on Marineville.
- Yes, sir.
- [Man On Loudspeaker] Attention.
This is Marineville Control.
All personnel stand by
for battle stations.
(dramatic music)
- Tower from Stingray.
Are we clear to leave, Marineville?
- Clear to go, Stingray.
(mysterious music)
Tower to power plant, commence
battle stations procedure.
- [Man On Loudspeaker] Battle
stations, battle stations,
battle stations, BWR.
(tense music)
- Acceleration, grade six.
- Phase six.
- Set course for Lull.
Turn into green lower five.
(mysterious music)
On course for the Island of Lull.
- Good work, Admiral.
Soon Stingray will arrive in
answer to your distress signal.
Her crew are-
- I love puppet gunplay.
- The ship will be mine.
Now go ahead of me to my underwater craft.
- You don't stand a chance.
Stingray will be here in an hour.
- That means Troy Tempest has
just one hour left to live.
(dramatic music)
- One hour at rate six.
That makes the Island of Lull dead ahead.
- Thanks, Phones.
Reduced to rate one.
Give me a surface video scan.
(mysterious music)
No visible sign of trouble.
- [Joel] Not yet.
- SBC, stand by to surface.
- Standing by.
- Right.
Blow one.
- Blow one.
- [Joel] Pull my finger.
- We're going ashore.
Say, is that toy fish aboard?
- Yeah, but this is no
time for practical jokes.
- This is no joke.
I got an idea we're going to need it.
Blow three, five, and seven.
- [Joel] And play the jazz.
(light jazz music)
- We're going ashore
to investigate, Marina.
But you'll be okay here?
(tense music)
- Good.
Stingray has arrived.
Now you're aboard my
craft, there is nothing
you can do to save them.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Levitating La-Z-Boys.
(tense music)
- You fiend.
You can't just sit there and
watch them go to their deaths.
- But I can, Admiral.
That is my mission.
And when they are
destroyed, I will be free
to take Stingray.
(tense music)
- What do you make of it, Phones?
- I don't know.
Well, the door's open.
Let's take a look.
- Hold it.
I'm not taking any chances.
Bring the toy fish.
- But Troy-
- Do as I say, Phones, do as I say.
(tense music)
- [Joel] The ol' toy fish.
- Just a few minutes, and
Troy Tempest will be no more.
- Henry, you must stop him.
- Quiet, Milly, the WASPs
know what they're doing.
- I sure hope you know
what you're doing, Troy.
- That makes two of us.
Okay, here we go.
(motor whirring)
Now just imagine that fish is
us walking towards the house.
Let's see what would have happened.
(tense music)
Keep down, Phones.
(dramatic music)
(explosions booming)
Just as I figured.
A booby trap.
- Yeah.
We could have walked right
into it, wasn't for you.
- And the admiral's code.
Come on.
- And the fish.
(dramatic music)
- So the famous Troy Tempest is cleverer
than I gave him credit
for, but the next time,
I will make certain.
- Look, Troy.
- That's our baby.
And I reckon the Admiral and
his wife are prisoners aboard.
Let's get back to Stingray fast.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] I just can't quit thinkin'
of that little toy fish gettin' exploded.
(dramatic music)
- Somehow Tempest must have
been warned of the trap.
Well done, Admiral.
But you will suffer for your foolishness.
- I don't scare easy.
You don't stand a chance with Stingray.
- But you do not know about my base.
There I will be safe.
(dramatic music)
- Flood cue.
- Okay, Phones, start sound scan.
They've got a head start.
(suspenseful music)
- Green zero-zero-two.
- Zero-zero-two.
(suspenseful music)
- Sound scan reports rock formation ahead.
- Decelerate to investigation cruise.
(suspenseful music)
- Red one-three-two.
There's a tunnel entrance dead ahead.
- Well, Phones, they must
have gone into the tunnel.
- Yeah.
And it's too small to take Stingray.
We could follow in the Aqua Sprite.
- [Troy] No good, Phones.
Too much noise.
We want to sneak up on 'em.
- Then there's only one answer.
Let's put on our skin
suits and use our sea bugs.
I'll get 'em.
- Now hold it, Phones.
Not so fast.
It's too risky.
We're not certain of the
length of that tunnel,
and our air supply could give out.
- Yeah, but Skipper the
admiral and his wife,
they're in danger.
- I know that, but we want
to stay alive to help 'em.
We'll have to take a sonic and
figure the tunnel's length.
Get to it, Phones.
(sonar beeping)
- Well, I'd say the tunnel's
about three miles long
with a cave at the end of it.
- Well, that's it.
The air supply would never last.
Phones, the escape hatch.
- Marina!
Marina!
(suspenseful music)
She must have heard us.
She's going into the tunnel.
- I guess she figured she'd
be the only one to help
because she can breathe underwater.
- Get the sea bugs.
We're going after her.
- But we'll never make it.
- We've gotta make it.
(explosions booming)
(upbeat music)
(suspenseful music)
Step on it, Phones.
- Just a minute.
There, now that does it.
- [Joel] They stay down pretty good
for being made outta wood.
(tense music)
- So Troy Tempest sends a
woman to fight his battles.
Come over here.
One false move and I'll fire.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Better do as he says.
- [Phones] Troy.
I've got trouble with my sea bug.
My speed's dropping.
- [Troy] Phones, keep calm.
I'm staying with you.
- [Phones] You go on, Troy.
Our air won't last at this speed.
Now that's for sure.
- [Troy] I'm staying with you, Phones.
Just keep going at the
best speed you can get.
- [Joel] Just let go and
let the threads drag ya.
- Now, what are Troy Tempest's plans?
Speak, do you hear me?
Speak!
- Leave her alone, you crazy fools.
- Quiet!
Marin, we must make the girl talk.
Fix things up at once.
- Yes, Gadeth.
- [Joel] He just said "lettuce."
"Yes, lettuce."
See what I mean?
Lettuce head.
- [Phones] How much further, Troy?
My air is running low.
- [Troy] And mine, Phones.
We've gotta keep going.
This tunnel can't be much longer.
- [Phones] Leave me, Troy.
You can make it.
- [Troy] Either we both make
it or we both don't make it.
I'm staying with you.
(dramatic music)
- Now talk, or you will die.
- [Joel] You're barking up the wrong tree.
She can't speak, she's from underwater.
- When the flame reaches the
line, the swordfish will drop.
You have less than 10
marine minutes to speak.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Marine minutes.
Jack the knife.
(tense music)
(Joel laughing)
Just cut those lines
and you can go faster.
- [Phones] My air, Troy.
It's finished.
Go on.
You'll have to leave me.
- [Troy] Keep going, Phones.
Keep going.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] I think it's a
good time to point out that-
- [Gadeth] Five marine minutes left.
- [Joel] These puppets
do their own stunts.
- Speak!
What are Troy Tempest's plans?
- [Troy] Phones, grab my hand.
My air's going too.
Must keep going.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Try to reason with it.
Still fighting.
- Are you okay, Phones?
- I guess so.
Thanks, Troy.
- Forget it.
Let's go find Marina.
- Let the girl go.
Can't you see she knows nothing?
- You must be crazy.
Just crazy.
- Speak, girl!
You have less than two minutes.
Troy Tempest sent to you here alone.
He was willing to risk your life.
He doesn't care about you.
- Don't move, anyone.
- Tempest.
- Release her or we fire.
(dramatic music)
(gunshots banging)
We gotta stop that candle burning.
(Joel laughing)
(gunshots banging)
(suspenseful music)
Have to draw their fire.
- That means me, Troy.
Better shot than I am, anyway.
(gunshots banging)
(suspenseful music)
(explosion booms)
- We haven't got time to
play this cool, Phones.
When I give the word, dive into the open
and blast that rock!
(gunshots banging)
(suspenseful music)
Now!
- [Joel] I love the way that guy moves.
(Joel laughs)
(explosion booming)
- Don't shoot!
We surrender!
- Keep 'em covered, Phones!
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] And he's made out of wood, too.
You know how dangerous that is?
- He did it!
Troy Tempest did it!
- Are you okay, Marina?
(tense music)
Don't worry.
We'll soon have you out of this.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Grr.
- Heavens, that was a close thing.
- All right then, Milly.
Oh, that girl's tops.
They tried to make her talk-
- But she just wouldn't
give you away, Captain.
- No sir, she didn't say a word.
- Well, there's a very good
reason for that, Admiral.
- You see, she can't speak.
She doesn't know how.
And even if she could, I know
she wouldn't have let us down.
Am I right, Marina?
(dramatic music)
- Oh, she says that now.
(alarm blaring)
- [Man On Loudspeaker] Attention.
Marineville tracking station calling.
Missile approaching, impact 30 seconds!
- Emergency battle stations!
- [Atlanta] Power plant, battle stations.
(suspenseful music)
- Fire WASP interceptor!
(explosion booming)
Tower to tracking station.
Imperative source of missiles located.
- [Man On Intercom] Approximate location
undersea, Commander.
Position South-Southwest 1800.
References 20, 21, and 22.
- That's a 200-mile radius.
Can't you get any closer than that?
- [Man On Intercom] Negative, sir.
Only approximate position available.
- Okay, tracking station.
Alert jet squadron, and Stingray, Atlanta.
I want that area searched.
- [Atlanta] Yes sir.
(dramatic music)
- Tower from Stingray, seaborne.
- Okay, Troy
Proceed at full speed to
position South-Southwest,
1800 reference 20, 22.
Thorough search of area vital.
Priority one.
- Okay, sir.
We're on our way.
- [Man On Loudspeaker]
Central control to jet squad.
Scramble.
(engines rumbling)
- Approaching the search area, Troy.
- Okay, Phones.
Start sound scan.
(sonar beeping)
- Area reference 20 negative.
- Right.
Moving to area 21.
- [Joel] Not area 21.
(sonar beeping)
- Area 21 negative.
Apart from an island, that is.
(dramatic music)
(engines rumbling)
- Okay, Phones.
Standby to surface.
We'll check it out.
Blow one.
- [Joel] Pull my finger
(mysterious music)
- Can you see anything, Troy?
- [Joel] Just a low-budget island.
- No, phones, this island's deserted.
That missile couldn't
have come from there.
(Joel mumbling)
- I guess we better check out area 22.
There's nothing here.
- Hmm, doesn't seem to be.
How about you, Marina?
You see anything?
- [Joel] She can't talk.
- Okay, that's it, then.
Tower from Stingray,
areas 20 and 21 negative.
Proceeding to area 22.
(solemn music)
(dramatic music)
Tower from Stingray.
Missile launched from island in area 21.
- Fire WASP interceptor!
- Yes, sir.
(suspenseful music)
- Finish that missile
before it has a chance
to get so close this time.
(suspenseful music)
(explosion booming)
Okay, Troy investigate the
island, but use extreme caution.
(dramatic music)
(explosions booming)
(doors closing)
- Hey, Crow, what do you know?
- I just got back from
Kokomo, Joel Hodgson.
- Anyway, hey Cambot,
bring it in a little bit,
I want to show 'em this...
I kind dabble a little bit
in genetic engineering myself
and I invented this,
it's my interpretation
of a man-eating plant.
- Ooh, that's very interesting.
- Yeah, as you know, you
can go back now, Cambot.
Anyway, as you know,
space is a great place
to develop new ideas.
This is my new invention
for the human race.
And you know how they
have airbags for cars,
but really they don't have anything
for anybody who drives motorcycles.
So I invented this.
- Wow, that blows my mind.
Being a human must be a rush.
- Yeah, it is, it really is, Crow.
Anyway, I think it's time to get going.
Stay tuned.
(Joel vocalizes)
(upbeat music)
- There must be some kind
of base beneath the island.
The easiest way to enter
would be down in the crater.
- Yeah.
We could meet another
missile on its way up.
- Exactly.
Come on, we'll dive and take a look around
beneath the water.
There could be another
entrance down there.
(suspenseful music)
Okay. Phones.
Now keep looking for some kind of opening.
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] What's happening, Joel Hodgson?
- [Joel] Well, these lettuce guys, wait-
- A cave mouth.
- Yeah.
It could lead us to the
base of the volcano.
Let's take a look.
(mysterious music)
- [Joel] Okay, well, this
one emperor guy tried to...
- [Crow] Is he the emperor?
- [Joel] No.
We're gonna have to wait till the break.
- There's a shaft above us, Troy.
- And I can see light.
(mysterious music)
Okay, we're going to surface, Phones.
- Blow one.
- [Joel] Pull my finger.
- [Crow] Blow one, I get it.
(Crow laughing)
(mysterious music)
(dramatic music)
- Okay, Phones.
Let's take a look at that
tunnel at the far end.
- Right.
- Marina, you just sit tight.
- [Joel] Watch these things.
Levitating La-Z-Boy recliners.
- [Crow] I had a brother
who could do that once.
(Crow laughing)
(dramatic music)
(eerie music)
- Troy, what's that?
- I don't know, but I don't like it.
(Joel chuckles)
- [Crow] They sure are
funny-looking for humans.
- My arm.
- [Joel] It's a boredom ray.
- I can't move it.
- [Joel] A disarming ray.
- Mine either.
It's numb.
- It must be a paralyzing
ray of some kind.
I can't move a muscle.
(eerie music)
- Troy.
- [Joel] Are they sweating or is that sap?
- Hardly speak.
(eerie music)
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] Forced to watch their own movie.
How horrible.
(Joel chuckles)
- Welcome to our base, Captain Tempest.
You are beneath the island Bahow.
- Who are you?
What do you want with us?
- All you need to know
is that we are going
to destroy Marineville and
you are going to help us.
- You're crazy.
I'll never do that.
- Ah, but you're will, Tempest.
All we require is some information.
- You'll get nothing outta me.
- No sir, me neither.
- [Crow] I like it.
- I know you are both brave men.
It would be a lengthy business
trying to make you talk,
unaided, but talk you shall.
Show them, Chidora.
- [Joel] Chidora?
(mysterious music)
Sounds like a kinda sweater.
(tense music)
(Crow chuckles)
It's your mystery date.
- [Crow] Are you ready?
- You hear me?
Release her.
- Shut up and listen, Tempest.
I want to know on what frequencies
Marineville's interceptors work.
- I get it.
You'll jam the interceptors
so your rockets
can get through and destroy Marineville.
- Very smart, Troy Tempest.
Now give me the information
or Marina will suffer.
Explain, Chidora.
- It is simple.
As I turn this control, the
electronic power increases.
Marina will be quite safe until
a thousand marine volts are reached.
Then she will die.
- Let her go.
Do you hear me?
Let her go!
- Certainly, Tempest.
When I have the correct
interceptor frequencies.
- Troy.
If we tell him, Commander Shaw, Atlanta,
all of Marineville will be wiped out.
- And if we keep quiet, Marina dies.
- [Gadeth] Well, Tempest, I am waiting.
(dramatic music)
- No deal, fella.
It's three lives against thousands.
- Very well.
Chidora, the voltage.
(tense music)
- 300 marine volts.
She can feel nothing yet, Tempest,
but the power is increasing.
(tense music)
- [Joel] His hair's standing on end.
- [Crow] I wouldn't know about hair.
- [Joel] Look at him sweating.
(tense music)
- Only 200 marine volts to go.
- [Crow] The lights are yellow.
They better clear the intersection.
- Still refuse to cooperate?
Very well.
Full power.
The fatal dose!
(solemn music)
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] I think she likes it.
- [Crow] Her head must be
made of fiberglass insulation.
- I'll talk.
- [Gadeth] Well, Tempest?
The frequencies?
- 2000 mega cycles.
Ultra nine-seven-five.
Cryptic zero-zero.
D-a-c.
- [Crow] Joel Hodgson,
that's my frequency.
- [Joel] Yeah.
- [Gadeth] Take them to the cell, Chidora.
They will remain our prisoners.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Does that mean I'm in trouble?
- [Joel] No, except the movie.
- [Crow] Good.
- In you go, and hurry.
I have much work to do on the missile.
- [Joel] I hope these two characters
were based on Tony Randall.
I'd like to share a cell with him.
(dramatic music)
- The prisoners are secure.
- Good.
Now we must alter our missile frequencies.
Come, Chidora.
- What now, Troy?
- Quick, give me one of your buttons.
- A button?
Troy, have you gone crazy?
- Don't argue, Phones, we haven't time.
The button, quickly.
- [Joel] Why doesn't he
use one of his own buttons?
- Marina, start ripping that cushion cover
into strips will ya?
(Crow mumbles)
- What's this all about?
- [Troy] Stick around and you'll see.
(dramatic music)
- Now work on the new frequencies.
This is going to be a long job, Chidora.
(mysterious music)
- Right, let's hope Lady
Luck of smiling at us.
Here goes.
- [Crow] Hopefully
she'll do more than that.
- Now we gently pull it in.
- Crow.
Oh!
- Missed.
Now this time it's gonna work.
- It's got to.
- Metric.
17 megavolts.
- [Joel] Why don't they just
use one of their threads.
- That means the electrostatic
gauge reads 7000 gyrometers.
- Check.
Increase hydraulic to three
quarters of a megacycle.
The weather report is favorable for firing
at first light, Nucella.
- Good.
The rocket will be ready.
This time we will not fail.
Marineville will be destroyed.
(tense music)
- Okay, you got it, Troy.
Now easy does it.
(tense music)
Has it come loose, Troy?
- I don't know.
We'll soon see.
Nearly there.
- Troy.
I hear footsteps.
- Right.
(suspenseful music)
- We are going to our
quarters now to rest, Tempest.
- [Joel] Sure they are.
- I believe it.
- It will be fired at dawn,
and you will be able to
watch the destruction
of Marineville on our monitors.
- Nice.
- Until dawn, then.
- [Carry] I'd be tired if I had to carry
a diving board around on my head.
(Joel laughing)
- Oh boy, was that close.
I thought sure he was gonna
notice the key had gone.
- Yeah, me too.
I want to take a look at that missile.
We'll wait until things quiet down.
Then we start.
(tense music)
- Are you nearly through, Troy?
It's about an hour till dawn.
- Okay, Phones.
I can't rush this job.
One false move and we'll
all be blown to paradise.
- Now he tells me.
(tense music)
- [Crow] Paradise sounds
better than this movie.
- Still no word from Stingray-
- [Joel] He's got a
remote commode, that guy.
- No, sir.
Oughtn't we to send out search planes?
- We'll give 'em another two hours.
(tense music)
- Well, we made it back okay, Phones.
- Yeah, just in time
- Missile ready for launch, Nucella.
- [Joel] I'm gonna get gum.
- Very well.
Now.
(missile booming)
- [Crow] But you haven't
told me what's going on.
But Joel, wait.
Joel!
- Launch complete.
- Get the prisoners from the cell.
I wish them to see the rocket strike.
(dramatic music)
(explosion booming)
(upbeat music)
- [Man On Loudspeaker] Attention.
Marineville tracking station calling.
Missile approaching.
Impact-
- [Crow] Joel, get your non-metallic
little human body back in here.
- Emergency!
Fire at once!
- I think it's the climax.
- [Joel] Okay, okay.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Down in front.
- [Joel] Okay.
What did I miss?
Oh.
- [Crow] I'm not telling you.
Ha, ha, ha.
(suspenseful music)
- [Man On Loudspeaker] Tracking
station to Marineville.
Interceptors negative missile,
unchecked, impact 30 seconds!
- What's happened, Father?
- The missile's homing
frequencies have been changed.
- [Joel] Looks like this is it.
- We'll never destroy it now.
There's nothing we can do.
(suspenseful music)
- When the light reaches
the end of the path,
Marineville will be finished.
(suspenseful music)
- [Man On Loudspeaker] Attention.
Attention.
Missile approaching Marineville.
Impact five seconds.
- Oh, father.
- [Crow] The missile's gonna hit the pan.
(missile whooshing)
(explosions booming)
(alarm blaring)
- Father, what happened?
It didn't explode.
We're okay.
- Yeah, but how long?
Attention Marineville.
Emergency remains.
Rocket disposal squad will get to work
on that missile immediately.
I want a report as soon as possible.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Oh, he's pacing, right?
- [Crow] His boots
weren't made for walking.
(Joel chuckles)
(siren wailing)
- What in thunder is
keeping that disposal squad?
They've been working for
hours on that missile.
- Yes, and at any time, we
could all be blown sky high.
Oh, wait, here comes the lieutenant.
- Missile is safe, sir.
- [Joel] Looks like Darrin Stephens
from the old "Bewitched" show.
- Disarmed before it hit Marineville.
- How's that?
- [Crow] Dick York or Dick Sargent?
- I think this note will explain, sir.
We found it in a red container
near the main centrifugal contact region.
- Atlanta, it's from Troy.
- From Troy?
- [Crow] From troy?
- This note it explains
that they are prisoners
in a base beneath Vile Island.
Say, the old son of a gun
disarmed that missile.
- He saved us.
- Yeah.
Now we've got to save
him, if it isn't too late.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] He looks like a certain
governor of Massachusetts.
(Joel chuckles)
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] Did George Lucas
do these special effects?
- [Joel] Shh.
- Attention undersea base.
- Sorry.
- Release your prisoners
or we will attack.
You have 30 seconds to surrender.
- They will not attack while we have
Tempest and his friends.
- That's where you're wrong.
Every member of the WASPs is prepared
to die if they have to.
If you don't surrender,
I guess we'll all die.
- [Joel] Not the WASPs that I know.
- We are quite safe as long as-
- [Joel] Hey, cut it out.
- With us.
(gunshots banging)
(suspenseful music)
(explosions booming)
They are attacking!
They have abandoned
Tempest and the others!
- No, no, it's still
blocked, they will withdrew.
- No they won't, Nucella.
We're all doomed.
(suspenseful music)
(gunshots banging)
(explosions booming)
- The place is on fire.
They will destroy us.
- Release the prisoners, Nucella.
It is our only chance.
(suspenseful music)
Terrainian aircraft!
We surrender!
Stop the attack.
(dramatic music)
- Jet squadron Spearhead from Stingray.
We have been released.
Undersea base has been abandoned.
We have a couple of prisoners on board.
- [Man On Intercom] Roger, Stingray.
We'll leave it to you.
Good hunting.
(dramatic music)
(laser blasting)
- [Joel] A butter ray.
(explosions booming)
- [Crow] Parkay.
- [Joel] Parkay ray?
(laser blasting)
(explosions booming)
(solemn music)
- I'll call you with more details soon.
- Right, thank you, sir.
- We've got trouble.
- We got trouble, all right.
(dramatic music)
- Maritamis reporting to Solaster Base.
Approaching target area.
- [Joel] His head kinda
looks like an end table.
(tense music)
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] I think that gun is my mother.
(Joel chuckles)
- Missile ejector on target.
Five miles.
Firing now.
- Hold on.
- Contact.
(missile whooshing)
(explosions booming)
(dramatic music)
(explosion booming)
(water splashing)
- [Crow] Do we have any
WD40 in the refrigerator?
- Suggest firing is a complete success.
- [Joel] I don't know, you have to check.
- Devastation force 10-plus.
Returning to Solaster to report.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Do you want anything?
- [Joel] No, I'm fine.
- [Crow] Okay.
You have to tell me what's going on.
- [Joel] Okay.
- Marineville control to Stingray.
(dramatic music)
Marineville control to Stingray.
Come in, Stingray.
- Stingray to Marineville.
Go ahead, Atlanta.
- Proceed to position
South-Southwest 1500,
reference five, Troy, and
investigate mysterious destruction
of the deserted island of Sanme.
- Okay, Marineville.
Changing course.
Will report later.
(dramatic music)
- Maritamis to Solaster Base.
Approaching the inner sea of Solaster.
Present depth, two miles
below bottom of Pacific Ocean.
(dramatic music)
Maritamis to Solaster Base.
Now below the Earth in the Solaster Sea,
approaching Solaster.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Key word here is Solaster.
- [Crow] Ah.
Boy, do I feel refreshed.
- [Joel] Well, you didn't miss anything.
Except the guy whose head
looks like an end table.
To Solaster base.
Request permission to enter city.
- [Crow] He's still there.
- [Joel] He's still there, and
he's going in the Solaster.
(dramatic music)
Maritamis to Solaster control.
Disembarking.
I will report to our mighty
leader in five marine minutes.
- [Man On Loudspeaker]
Attention all Solaster.
- [Joel] And you know how long that is.
- [Man On Loudspeaker]
I, your mighty leader,
summon Corda, my advisor.
Corda, report to your
mighty leader at once.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Nice.
- [Crow] Your mother was a thimble.
(Joel chuckles)
- [Corda] Mighty leader,
I am here to advise you.
May I see your face?
- I have decided that now we know
our powerful missile
ejector is successful,
we are ready to launch our
attacks on the Terrainians.
- Yes.
Long have we awaited the day when we
take over the surface lands.
- With our new weapon of destruction,
the Terrainians will
not withstand our might.
One missile from our cannon
will set up a chain reaction
and destroy an entire landmass,
even an entire continent,
if necessary.
I am now ready to receive Maritamis.
- Of course.
Maritamis, the mighty leader awaits you.
Maritamis comes now, mighty leader.
- The medal of honor, Corda.
Maritamis has earned the
decoration for his work this day.
- [Joel] He should get
a lamp for a decoration.
- May I stand before you?
- Come, Maritamis.
Let me see the face of a truly brave man.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Ouch.
- For your bravery and devotion to duty,
you will have the honor to lead the attack
on the surface land.
You will begin the invasion by destroying
the West coast of the area known
as the United States of America.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] That's where
you're from, Joel Hodgson?
- [Joel] Mm-hmm.
- [Crow] You're kibble.
- [Joel] That's right.
- Say, Troy.
Sounds like-
- Unless they do something.
About 10,000 feet down.
- Okay, Phones.
Get a bearing on it.
We'd better check it out before
proceeding with
Marineville's instructions.
- It's moving real fast, Troy.
But I don't figure that it's
constructed of a material.
I can't identify it.
- Right.
Let's go down and take a look.
(tense music)
Okay, Phones, dive.
- Dive, dive, dive.
- Main ballast 1000.
- 1000.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] That's what he said.
- 400 feet.
Unidentified craft increasing in speed.
- Okay, let's get after it.
Increase rate of dive.
Main ballast 3000.
- Main ballast 3000.
(suspenseful music)
2000 feet.
- Increase speed to rate three.
- Rate three.
(tense music)
Say, the other craft is rising.
- Yeah, I can see it at red zero-zero-two.
(dramatic music)
Keep at a safe distance, Phones.
We'll observe it for a while.
I want to know some more about it.
- Right.
It doesn't seem to have spotted us.
(dramatic music)
We seem to be heading for
the West coast of America.
- I don't it, Phones.
I don't like it one bit.
- [Joel] You're not the only
ones, I used to live there.
- [Crow] How awful.
(dramatic music)
- Why, it's surfacing, Troy.
- Okay, Phones, blow one.
- Blow one.
- [Joel] Pull my finger.
(Crow chuckles)
- Maritamis to Solaster Base.
Preparing missile ejecta for attack
on West coast of America.
(dramatic music)
Maritamis to Solaster.
On target.
20 marine seconds to firing.
Setting missile to full power.
(dramatic music)
- It stopped.
Do you think we've been spotted?
- No.
Look, there's a gun mounted on it.
It's taking aim!
(suspenseful music)
(explosions booming)
(upbeat music)
- Okay, people of Earth,
let me show you around
the Satellite of Love a little bit.
These are the vacuum flowers right here.
Hey Cambot, bring it in a
little bit so they can see this.
These things are really important to me
because they're the only living thing,
carbon-based life form, on this space...
This one doesn't look too good.
They're usually pretty...
Oh, gah.
Oh.
You are sick, aren't you?
Oh golly.
You know, they always say
that pollen makes us sick,
but they never say what
we might do to flowers.
Hey, Gypsy.
(Gypsy shrieks)
Hey, could you bring my doctor's stuff in?
I got a flower in here that's sick.
(Gypsy shrieks)
Needs some help.
Yeah.
Oh, well, it's a carbon-based life form.
He's sick, he's different
than you are, Gypsy.
Let me just dig in your bag.
(Gypsy hissing)
(Gypsy shrieking)
- Oh, god, what's going on?
Wait a minute.
Here.
Here, oh, it's okay, honey.
Here, I'm just gonna
try to get it off here.
Here, wait a sec.
Here, put your head back a little bit.
That's right.
Crow?
- [Crow] Yes, Joel Hodgson.
- Hey, bring Beeper in here.
Gypsy's contracted some
sort of weird alien
strain of disease, I need
you in here right away.
- Ouch.
- [Crow] It's toasted.
- Oh, jeez.
Oh, we're getting movie sign.
Can you run on it, Gypsy?
Okay.
(alarm buzzes)
(doors opening)
(suspenseful music)
- Phones, number one sting.
- Number one.
(suspenseful music)
- 10.
Nine.
Eight.
- Fire number one sting.
- [Phones] Fire one.
- Three
Two.
One.
(explosions booming)
(tense music)
- Good shootin', Cap.
- Maritamis to Solaster.
I'm under attack, abandoning
craft in escape unit.
(dramatic music)
(explosions booming)
- [Joel] He's escaping in a cigarette.
(tense music)
- Reduce speed to rate one.
We'll pick up survivors.
(suspenseful music)
- No sign of survivors, Troy.
- Hmm, I'm not surprised.
Let's collect some samples
of the wreckage for analysis.
We've gotta find out
what this is all about.
(solemn music)
How much longer are those scientists
gonna be with their report?
- Hold on, Troy.
You only brought the
wreckage in two hours ago.
- I know, sir, but all the time we wait,
the whole world could be in danger!
- We can't move, Troy, until we know
where that craft originated from.
I'm hoping the lab boys can tell us.
(tense music)
- Have the location scanners picked up
the Terrainian base, Corda?
- A submerged ocean door has been traced
on the West coast of the
United States of America.
From soundings taken,
base is 10 miles inland,
and our surface intelligence tells us
its name is Marineville.
- Then Maritamis will
make all speed to the area
in missile ejector number two.
This Marineville must be wiped out.
- Marineville scientists
say there's no doubt
the materials used to
build the alien craft
came from the undersea
area around position
South-Southwest 2100 reference nine.
- That's the West Pacific.
Let's check the ocean map.
- [Atlanta] Reference nine?
Why, that's one of the
deepest parts of the sea
in the entire world.
- Don't worry, we'll make it in Stingray.
- Yes, you'd better start
proving that, Tempest.
Atlanta, call action stations.
(tense music)
- [Crow] Joel?
- [Joel] Yeah, Crow?
- [Crow] Do we have any beer nuts left?
- For launch, Commander.
- [Joel] No people food for you.
- [Crow] I'm just trying to assimilate.
(dramatic music)
- Missile now set for full power.
Contact for launch in 20 seconds.
(suspenseful music)
- It's aiming directly for us!
- 10.
Nine.
- Attention, Marineville
tracking station calling
unidentified craft located in our area.
- Emergency.
Battle stations one, two, and three.
- Two.
One.
Zero.
Fire!
(cannon firing)
(tense music)
- Tracking station calling.
Enemy missile launched.
Impacts 10 seconds.
- Fire WASP interceptors.
(suspenseful music)
Em
We made it, Atlanta, but only just.
Call Stingray.
Tell 'em we're under attack.
- Yes, sir.
Tower to Stingray, Tower to Stingray.
Come in, Captain Tempest.
There's no reply.
Marineville's radio's dead.
It must be due to the explosion.
- I can't contact the tower, Troy.
- Must be a radio fault.
- Get the radio division to
set up an emergency antenna.
We must renew contact with Stingray.
- Yes, sir.
But it'll take some time.
- Just relay the message, Lieutenant.
I'll fix the schedules.
- Yes, sir.
Marineville tracking station calling.
Now established missile attack originated
from unidentified vessel
20 miles from coast.
- Well, let's hope Stingray can tackle it.
- [Joel] That scene looks familiar.
- I'm picking up a sound,
Troy, and it's identical
to the missile we blew up the other day.
- That's our baby.
Let's go.
(dramatic music)
- Closing in fast.
- Okay.
Reduce speed.
Let's shadow him.
That way he'll lead us to his base.
(dramatic music)
- Maritamis to Solaster.
Returning to base.
Being shadowed by
Terrainian vessel Stingray.
Will lure enemy to our
domain and then destroy it,
if it survives the pressure
of our deep waters.
(suspenseful music)
- We're nearing the deepest
part of the ocean, Troy.
- That means the craft must
be near its base by now.
Keep going with the sound scanners.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] You know, it's almost like
a couple of TV shows edited together.
It's not even like a real movie.
- [Crow] I'm enjoying it, though.
Shh.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] That looks like
the same tunnel as before.
- [Crow] I lied.
- Now what?
- We can't lose it now.
We're going in after it.
- [Crow] I'm going to go check on Gypsy.
- [Joel] Okay.
She in sickbay?
- Yep.
- Okay.
- It's fantastic.
We're increasing our
depth all the time, Troy.
- Yeah, pressure above is pretty terrific.
This is the tough
Stingray's ever stood up to.
- If pressure builds up anymore,
it may not stand up to it.
- Watch the pressure gauges, Phones.
(sonar beeping)
There goes the depth gauge.
How much deeper does this tunnel go?
- This soundings show
we're descending, Troy.
How about the hull?
Will it stand the pressure
or will it collapse?
- I'll let you know.
- [Joel] Milk's leaking in from outside.
- That's the hull, and it
doesn't sound very reassuring.
(glass cracks)
- Board observation
paneling, it's cracked.
We've gotta head back, Stingray
won't take much more of this.
- Reduce speed, Phones.
We're going through with this.
With any luck, she'll hold for a while.
Look, ahead.
The end of the tunnel.
- Yeah, but we're still going down.
And then the sounding
equipment is failing.
We're gonna be navigating
blind before long.
Gee, Troy.
- [Joel] Just open a window.
- I can't stand this pressure.
- No sign of our friend.
We've lost him.
Phones.
This is a subterranean sea.
An ocean below the Pacific.
- [Crow] What happened?
- That accounts for the great depth.
- [Joel] They're in a subterranean sea.
- And there's approach
lights on the sea bed.
(mysterious music)
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] More milk.
Milk's...
- Pretty bad now.
I can hardly move my arms.
- [Joel] Why don't they
just open a window?
- [Phones] It's increasing every minute.
- If we don't find him soon, Phones,
we'll have to turn back.
Stingray won't take much more
of this before she folds up.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Gypsy says hi.
- [Joel] Oh, good.
- [Crow] Another Penzoil enema,
she'll be as good as new.
- Pretty near.
- Yeah.
I can see lights ahead.
(ominous music)
- Phones, look at that underwater city.
Must be their base.
- [Joel] That's no city,
that's a battle station.
(ominous music)
Asleep at the wheel.
- Phones, there's a missile firing craft,
and it's got us right in its sights.
We've gotta destroy it, before it gets us.
I'll need your help.
- [Crow] Get 'em, get 'em.
- The Terrainians' craft
has withstood the pressure.
But from the attitude of the
vessel, their crew haven't.
(mysterious music)
- Phones.
Come on, boy.
We're in trouble.
- Now for the kill.
Launching missile in 10 seconds.
10.
- [Joel] Is that 10 marine seconds ?
Come on, Phones.
Three, zero, zero, nine.
Sting one.
(dramatic music)
- One.
Zero.
(laser blasting)
(explosion booming)
- [Joel] You know, maybe he
should get a shorter countdown.
He keeps getting blasted.
- [Crow] That's the
problem with undersea life.
- [Joel] It's those marine seconds.
(explosions booming)
(upbeat music)
- Oh, I must've passed out.
Say, the cannon's exploded.
If you can help me, Marina,
we can destroy the city.
(laser blasting)
- [Joel] That's your answer
to everything, isn't it?
Destroy the city.
- [Crow] Destroy the city.
(explosion booming)
(dramatic music)
Joel?
- [Joel] Yeah?
- [Crow] Is it possible
for a robot to be bored?
- [Joel] I don't think so.
- [Crow] Oh.
- Okay, Marina.
Let's get outta here
before Stingray collapses
like a paper bag.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] You ever
collapsed like a paper bag?
- [Crow] No.
- [Joel] It's not pretty.
- [Crow] I think it wouldn't be.
(dramatic music)
- Well, we've learned one
thing out of all this, Tempest.
Our scientists, designers,
and indeed we ourselves
are not infallible.
Marineville's early warning
system needs improving.
Stingray must be prepared
to go even deeper
than the deepest ocean.
- [Crow] I have to drain my radiator
- [Joel] Okay.
- Man has never before encountered.
We've all gotta start working right away
to equip ourselves for any event.
- Right, dismissed.
Okay, Atlanta.
Let's get started.
There's no time to lose.
- [Man On Loudspeaker] Marineville
tracking station calling.
Remote control undersea survey probe
in position South-Southwest
200, reference four.
- Probe signal burying
at 55 and eight-zero
sonic mega bars coming in.
- Subload ref gold.
Start a EG.
Yes, we'll be through
with this section soon.
- Yes, Commander.
This sure is a swell way
to survey the ocean floor.
- I know it, Lieutenant.
Kinda like the satellites
that go up to explore space.
- Yeah, no manpower actually endangered.
Small team required to
note the probe's findings,
that's all.
- Yes, I know another
guy who likes the idea.
He doesn't have to do any work.
He can go out and enjoy himself.
(light jazz music)
- [Joel] Yeah.
(Joel snapping fingers)
- You know, this probe
has me worried, Phones.
- In what way, Troy?
- Well, some bright guy could get the idea
that all undersea vessels should be packed
with unmanned instruments.
- Then you'd be out of a job.
- Yeah, that's what I mean.
- Gee, Troy, you don't think
it'd to come to that, do ya?
- Relax, Phones.
I was only kiddin'.
- All the same, just thick.
Here we are, nice and snug while sea probe
is in that cold old sea
doing all the work for us.
(dramatic music)
(sonar beeping)
- [Joel] Sounds like
there's a cuckoo clock
on that sea probe.
(sonar beeping)
(mysterious music)
Drives fish crazy.
(dramatic music)
- [Commander] What's
happening, Lieutenant?
The signal's fading.
- The probe seems to have gone
beneath the ocean bed, sir.
- What do you mean beneath the ocean bed?
There are no fissures
or cracks in that area.
Wait, there's a submerged
extinct volcano there,
and the crater appears to be enormous.
- Yeah.
A Magnum.
The biggest bottle of
champagne they've got.
I ordered it when we came in.
- Aww, gee, Troy, you sure
are living it up tonight.
- And why not?
We deserve it just this once, I guess.
- Hey Crow.
- Hey Joel Hodgson.
What did I miss?
- [Joel] Nothing, the same thing,
they destroyed the underwater city
and now we're back at Marineville.
- [Crow] What's the tally now?
- [Joel] Three alien
civilizations have been wiped out.
- [Crow] That's a good day.
- That's the tower.
Hold the champagne.
What's wrong, Commander?
- [Commander] Plenty.
- [Joel] These guys never get a break.
- I want you to report
to the tower immediately
so that I can fill you
in with all the details.
And I want Stingray to carry
out a full investigation.
(tense music)
- [Joel] Sounds like it's
time to lower the city again.
- [Crow] It's the Conga music.
(dramatic music)
It's nice that they've
made the transformation
from standard alarms to Conga music.
- Stingray seaborne.
- Okay, Troy.
Proceed to position
South-Southwest 2000 reference-
- [Joel] He's talking
into one of those things
you examine your ears with.
- [Commander] You'd better
wear the high frequency
tracking pack in case you're
pulled down to the volcano
like the probe.
- Yes, sir.
That'll keep us in signal
contact up to a depth
of four miles from the ocean bed.
- Four miles?
No extinct volcano can be that deep.
- We've come up against
stranger things than that
beneath the sea.
- [Crow] I didn't need no...
Nevermind.
- Rate six.
(tense music)
- Stingray in area reference four, sir.
- Okay, Atlanta.
Keep a close track.
If anything is gonna happen, it'll be
within the next few seconds.
(suspenseful music)
- Crater dead ahead.
- This is where the trouble started.
Stand by, Phones.
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] They're lucky to
find an extinct volcano.
I didn't even know they were endangered.
- Hey, we're going down!
We're being pulled down!
- Blow three and seven.
We've gotta keep her on an even keel.
- [Joel] Pull my finger.
- Marineville from Stingray.
We're being pulled into the volcano.
- [Commander] Stingray from tower.
I didn't get your last message.
Please repeat last message.
- Start high-frequency
tracking pack, Phones.
Normal radio contact fading.
- The tracking pack's operating.
- Yeah.
They're going beneath the ocean bed.
Tap in again, Atlanta.
Cypher signal is our only contact
with Stingray from now on.
(mysterious music)
- We're a thousand feet
beneath the ocean bed.
- Operate sounding echo.
I want to know how deep this crater is.
(tense music)
- [Crow] Oh, it's much deeper than that.
- [Joel] Echo.
(gentle music)
(dramatic music)
(sonar beeping)
- Jumpin' catfish.
I thought we'd never get that echo.
- Two and a half miles, Troy.
That's the crater's depth.
- Now we want to find
out what's waiting for us
at the bottom.
- [Crow] Why are they
monitoring their heart rate
at such a low depth
- Tracking signal half strike.
- That's two miles beneath the sea bed.
Thank heavens we know Stingray can stand
that water pressure.
- Less than 2000 feet to bottom, Troy.
- Nearly two and a half miles.
And they're still increasing depth rate.
- Why doesn't Troy slow her up?
Blow tanks, Troy, now.
- Blow all tanks.
Now.
(dramatic music)
- We're going faster.
- How much further?
- 200 feet.
This is it.
(mysterious music)
- We're slowing down.
- 20 feet to go.
- [Crow] That's very well
for the bottom of a crater
of an abandoned volcano
in the bottom of the sea.
- [Joel] I was just gonna say that.
- [Crow] I beat you this time.
- What is this place?
- I can't say, Troy,
it's difficult to see.
(ominous music)
(suspenseful music)
- Phones.
Look, there's some kinda door over there.
- [Man] Attention, Terranians.
Listen carefully.
You will swim out of your
craft towards the door.
It is an airlock.
- Where's that voice coming from?
- It's all around us, Troy.
- [Man] Approach the airlock.
- What do we do?
- My first thought is to
hightail it outta here.
- [Man] Obey me, or it
will be disastrous for you.
- What does it mean?
- That, I guess.
(tense music)
- [Crow] That would be
disastrous all right.
- The tracking signal's been constant
for 15 minutes, Father.
- Yeah.
Registering a depth of
two and one half miles
beneath the ocean.
- Well, what could have happened?
Why doesn't the signal change?
- [Joel] Maybe they're ignoring her.
- [Crow] I sure would.
- Obey the rules or we'll
give you a penicillin shot.
Right where it counts.
(Joel chuckles)
(tense music)
(water bubbling)
- Where do we go from here?
- Yeah.
There's no other door.
- [Man] Now, operate the control.
- Man said "Operate the control."
This must be it.
- We're going down.
- Yeah, and what a pace.
(signal beeping)
- We can be pretty sure
they're still okay, Atlanta.
- Yes, father, but they're
going deeper, and so swiftly.
It's almost as if they're heading
for the center of the Earth.
(ominous music)
- How deep are we, Phones?
- I don't know.
We must be about four miles
beneath the ocean bed, Troy.
- And we're on our own.
Marineville will have
lost all track of us.
(signal fading)
- It's gone, Father.
We've lost contact.
- Yeah.
They're beyond the transmitter's range.
Over four miles beneath the sea bed.
(explosions booming)
(upbeat music)
(Gypsy groaning)
- People of Earth.
As you can see, some alien form of disease
has infected my satellite and affected
all the robots and
carbon-based life forms.
- How's he doing, Joel Hodgson?
- Well, it's kinda hard to tell, Crow,
with this weird snake
thermometer I've got.
- This might be a bad time to bring it up,
Joel Hodgson, but wouldn't that make it
a rectal thermometer?
- Yuck.
- Ew.
(Gypsy shrieking)
- Oh, jeez.
- Uh-oh.
- Crow, we gotta find
out what this stuff is
before it gets serious, ugh.
- I don't know what it
is, but it's certainly
not one of the four food groups.
- That's for sure.
It's affected the robots, the
plant life, everything but...
- Humans?
(Joel sneezing)
- Oh, Crow, we got movie sign.
We gotta get outta here.
Let's go.
(alarm buzzes)
(doors opening)
- We're slowing up.
(tense music)
- [Man] Welcome to Voldana, Terrainians.
- [Joel] I don't know what
happened, I just sat down.
- [Crow] Okay, Joel Hodgson.
- [Joel] Isn't that Memphis furniture?
- You have arrived just in time.
- Who are you?
- Memphis?
- What is this place?
- My name is Turata.
This is Fragil.
We are the sole survivors of Zentralius,
the mighty civilization that
has lived under the Earth
for thousands of years.
- Alas, this room is the only
part of our dynamic city left,
for a great disaster struck.
- You mean every one
of your people is dead?
- Yes, Terranian.
- [Crow] Not everyone.
- When the volcano, became active.
I will explain.
(ominous music)
- [Joel] Oh, that' chart's real handy.
- Built within the shaft
of the dormant volcano.
We were luckily-
- Central control.
And Volandria's right there.
- Destroyed by the lava, huh?
- [Turata] Yes.
We managed to secure and
seal the protecting door.
- What happened then?
- The activity subsided and we were safe.
- Until now.
If you listen carefully, you can hear
the fury of the volcano,
just beyond these very walls.
(tense music)
- [Crow] That's what happens when you make
a seal of protection.
(Joel chuckles)
- Soon the volcano will erupt again.
Then our last refuge will be destroyed.
- That is why we used our
electronic suction apparatus
to draw in the first crack.
- You mean a vacuum.
- I don't understand.
- Like you, we cannot breathe in water.
We needed the crack to reach the terrain.
- But alas, the craft we
chose was full of instruments.
There was no room for us.
- So you drew Stingray down, eh?
- But why all the threats
with the missiles?
That wasn't very friendly.
- [Crow] It was full of instruments?
Music is important, but isn't life good?
- [Joel] It was filled
with the marine gold.
(volcano rumbling)
- Sounds like the volcano's ready to blow.
We better get outta here.
- Yes, but how do we get to
your ship from the airlock?
- Stingray's hatches open.
We can swim straight in.
There's only one problem.
- [Crow] It's full of water.
- Only got two sets of breathing gear.
- In that case, there is no problem.
We will take the breathing apparatus.
- You dirty rats.
- The guns.
- [Joel] Water rats.
- But the volcano-
- One more second and you die now!
- He means it, Phones.
Maybe there's some other
way out of this mess.
Do as he says.
- [Crow] No, that's not it.
(Joel chuckles)
- Come, Fragil, we must be leaving.
We would not want to
prolong your suffering.
We are humane people.
(suspenseful music)
(gunshot bangs)
(explosion booming)
- [Crow] Don't you have
to be human to be humane?
- [Joel] Yeah.
Looks like they're gonna
have a puppet hibachi.
(Crow chuckles)
- [Crow] Goodness gracious.
- And the lava's spreading.
- [Joel] Wouldn't be
lava if it didn't spread.
- There's only one hope.
- It'd be a rock.
- Marina.
(solemn music)
- [Crow] Their hair will rust.
(Joel chuckles)
- [Joel] Honk the horn at 'em.
- [Crow] Maybe if she flashes
the brights, they'll go away.
- [Turata] What do we do now?
The hatch is closed, we cannot get in.
- [Joel] Take off your swim gear.
- [Crow] Will that make
them easier to get in?
- [Joel] No.
So it wasn't that funny.
(Crow laughing)
Thank you.
- The Terrainians have
played a little trick on us.
Now it is our turn.
We will get them up here-
- [Crow] It would
probably make that problem
seem less important, though.
(suspenseful music)
They could wait for it to
harden and sell it as soap.
(Joel chuckles)
- The whole place is gonna collapse.
(suspenseful music)
- We must act swiftly if we are to escape.
- The Terranianians will give no trouble.
They are unarmed, remember,
and they are experienced enough
to manage without breathing
gear until we reach the hatch.
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] Because that's
the kind of guys they are.
- [Joel] Humane.
- [Crow] Pardon.
- Phones.
The elevator's coming down.
They must be returning.
(tense music)
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] Wow, baked beans.
- I do not see them.
Ah, they must have collapsed.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] No, he must've collapsed.
- We're not finished yet,
but I guess you two are.
Get 'em into the elevator, Phones, hurry.
- [Joel] And remember, all these puppets
are doing their own stunts, Crow.
- [Crow] That's important
when you're a puppet.
- [Joel] At what point does
a puppet quit being a puppet
and become a costume, Crow?
(tense music)
- [Crow] When he pays his union dues.
- [Joel] Good one.
- [Crow] Thank you. (chuckles)
- What are you going to do with us?
- We're taking you back to
Marineville, if we make it.
And that's more than you deserve.
- What are our chances, Troy?
- Well, it all depends
whether this elevator
moves faster than the lava, Phones.
And if the volcano doesn't suddenly blow.
(suspenseful music)
- [Joel] Pull my finger.
- [Crow] I'd like to bet on
the elevator to place, please.
- [Joel] There's that milk again.
- [Crow] Remember, kids,
milk and lava don't mix.
- Okay, Phones, hold your breath.
(tense music)
- [Joel] Pretty good for
seven miles under the sea.
- [Crow] Not bad.
Their ears aren't even bleeding.
(Joel chuckles)
(explosions booming)
That's what it is to be a good aquanaut.
(suspenseful music)
(explosions booming)
♪ Smoke under water ♪
(Joel chuckles)
♪ Fire in the sky ♪
♪ Smoke under water ♪
(suspenseful music)
- Nearly there, Troy.
- When we hit the ocean,
dive to the seabed.
You want to be out of the line of fire
when the volcano blows.
(tense music)
- [Crow] What about the submarine
with the soundtrack musicians?
(suspenseful music)
They're always the first to go.
(explosions booming)
- Tower to Stingray.
Are you okay?
Come in, Stingray.
Troy!
Speak to me.
- Hang on, Phones.
We've gotta ride out this tidal wave.
- [Crow] Now that's hanging 10.
- Stingray from tower.
Are you okay?
Answer me, Troy.
Troy!
Come in, Stingray.
This is Atlanta.
Are you okay?
- Tower from Stingray.
We're okay, Atlanta.
- Oh, Troy.
You're safe.
- Yeah, we're safe.
And we've got a couple of passengers, too.
Tell the commander to
have the cooler ready.
These are real unpleasant guys.
Oh, and tell Luigi to have
the champagne standing by.
I guess we've earned it.
(light jazz music)
- [Joel] Think the lab
boys will cut 'em open?
- [Crow] We can only hope.
(light jazz music)
- [Joel] Looks like Red Skelton on bass,
Sid Caesar on drums and
Elvis Costello at the piano.
- [Crow] What a combo.
Swing it.
This is where we came in.
(Atlanta chuckles)
(Joel and Crow chuckling)
- [Joel] Oh boy.
(explosions booming)
(upbeat music)
(tense music)
Well, that's the end of the show.
Hey, stay tuned back there.
When we get back to the
main part of the show.
- [Crow] We could review
the show, Joel Hodgson.
- [Joel] Yeah, we could
be Siskel and Ebert.
- [Crow] I'll be the fat
guy, you be the bald guy.
- [Joel] Okay.
Well, what did you think?
- [Crow] Well, I thought
it was long, boring,
kinda tedious and stupid, but
I have to give it a claws-up
because I kinda sympathize
with the puppets.
- [Joel] Yeah. (chuckles)
Yeah, what really always baffled me
is how they could keep those puppets
from floating to the surface
all the time, you know?
- [Crow] It's amazing, though.
I will have to give a definite thumbs-up
for the special effects used.
- [Joel] Yeah, I definitely think so.
And how they got that
fire to go on underwater?
- [Crow] Smoke in the water.
It was incredible.
- [Joel] There's deep purple right now.
You see how they're using
that deep purple on there?
- [Crow] Oh, very psychedelic.
Almost funkadelic.
- [Joel] Yeah, it was a
confunktion of sorts, I would say.
And do you think he had a thing going
with Atlanta or was it with Marina?
- [Crow] It could be both.
He was kind of a underwater stud.
- [Joel] He was.
- [Crow] Well, I'm gonna go
clean up the main control room.
- Okay, I'll meet you back over there.
Here we go, let's get outta here.
(dramatic music)
(doors closing)
All right.
What did you think of that movie?
I kinda liked it.
In fact, I'm expecting
a lot of great things
to come from Troy Tempest.
Like, I think his distinctive
walk could really catch on.
Think I got it?
Well, anyway, one thing
I wanted to tell you
before you went is thanks
a lot for joining me
here on "Mystery Science Theater 3000,"
and that if you pay
attention to the number
that's being flashed on your screen,
you can call me, if
everything works out okay,
you can call me up here at the satellite
and leave a message.
It should transmit, it's
something I kinda Jerry-rigged.
I'm not sure if it'll
work, but if you put in
a good response, maybe end up on the air
in a couple of weeks or something,
you might want to keep watching.
Anyway, I had one more invention
I wanted to show you, too.
This is a thing I made
for more people on Earth.
It's for a guy who would
happen to play bagpipes,
but they're electric.
(vacuum whirring)
(dissonant music)
The reason why I made this is so that
the guy could sing along
while he played, you know?
(vacuum whirring)
(dissonant music)
♪ Amazing grace ♪
♪ How sweet ♪
♪ The sound ♪
♪ That ♪
I can also do Led Zepplin tunes.
♪ She's got a whole lotta love ♪
(vacuum whirring)
(dissonant music)
♪ A whole lotta love ♪
♪ She's got a whole lotta love ♪
- Bravissimo, bravo, bravo.
- Oh, thanks, Crow.
- Might I say that that
was an amazingly beautiful
performance on the bagpipe.
- Thanks.
I'm glad you liked it.
- The walk was very nice as well.
- Wow, thanks.
You know, everything's worked out okay
since we had that epidemic
of that strange foam
from outer space, you know,
Gypsy's out sky munching
on the spiral on down,
I got over my sickness,
I'm doing okay.
You know, everything's
worked out all right.
- Yes, it has.
I wonder what it was, though.
Maybe it was an unknowable,
but important gesture
in the grand scheme of
things, you know, God blinked?
- Hmm.
Nah.
- Or maybe the virus
was a biological misfit,
and like the Andromeda strain,
became inert and eventually
blew over the Eastern seaboard.
- Interesting idea, but I don't think so.
- Hmm.
Joel?
- Yeah, Crow.
- Did you ever wonder
that maybe this spaceship
isn't really a spaceship at all,
but a television set
built for the amusement
of the viewing audience,
and I'm not really a robot,
but a puppet built to look like a robot,
who is in reality being controlled
by a puppeteer under this very table.
And you're not a scientist/inventor
trapped in outer space,
but just a comedian playing
a part on a television show
that you wrote.
- Hmm.
No, I don't think so either.
Somehow.
You know, Crow, one thing
I always wanted to ask you
is why is it that you never foam?
- Because I thought I'd save it
for the end of our transmission.
- Oh, great idea.
You serious?
Golly, ick.
I guess that's it, folks.
We'll see ya.
You are sick.
- Goodbye.